Curriculum Vitae Ron Valstar

personal info

Ron Valstar BA / MA de Kempenaerstraat 149 1051 CM Amsterdam 06 33697212

ron@ronvalstar.nl www.ronvalstar.nl www.sjeiti.com

born 21-04-1974 Apeldoorn



profile

I'm a dedicated front-end developer with more than twelve years experience in the world of digital media.

Because of my education and work as a graphic designer, interaction designer and programmer I am able look at a project form all perspectives. I have a very broad range of highly developed skills which I nurture and expand.

For solo projects I mostly work at the Keizerrijk, a workplace that I share with other freelancers. I also like to work on location as part of a team for larger projects.

skills

programming

Flash Actionscript 3 (FDT, Papervision3D, Away3D, pureMVC, Box2D, Greensock, amfPHP etc...)

Javascript (jQuery, Prototype, Scriptaculous)

HTML, XML, CSS (semantic and strict XHTML, HTML5, CSS3)

PHP/mySQL (Wordpress, Drupal, Codeigniter, Propel,)

Java / Processing

Lingo (Director)

interaction design

prototyping

user interface design

information visualisation

functional design

wireframing

conceptualisation

use cases

graphic design (Filter Forge, Photoshop, Illustrator)

illustration

concept art

textures

logos

page layouts

education

1999-2000 HKU: European Media Master of Arts, Interactive Multi Media (MA)

1996-1999 HKU: Interaction Design (BA)

1993-1996 CIBAP: Reclame

1992-1993 Basisopleiding reclame, LOI (tijdens dienstplicht)

1987-1992 HAVO

work experience

2007-2010 freelance interaction designer (portfolio)

2000-2007 co-founder of Shapers

1998-2000 freelance webdesigner

projects (short selection)

06-2010

deepRED Generated by www.PDFonFly.com at 10/5/2010 6:13:46 AM URL: http://ronvalstar.nl/cv.html

(deepRED)

An HTML5 website with lots of streaming video (no Flash). I advised the client on the technology concerning different platforms and eventually developed the end product.

02-2010

Allerhande

(Lukkien)

I was front-end actionscripter in the Fabrique/Lukkien/freelancers SCRUM team that developed the Allerhande website.

10-2009

Vacansoleil

(Lukkien)

Front-end Flash as3 development for a zoomable paralax vacation website.

05-2009

3D panoramas

(Iwan Baan)

User interface design and front-end Flash as 3 development for an application that links 3-dimensional panoramic views for architectural photography.

04-2009

Kees Kroot

(Pool Worldwide)

Advice and Flash development for a site that combines flat photograpy with Papervision3D to create a realistic view of Kees's head with stuff popping out.

02-2009

Rekentuin

(UVA)

Development of a serious gaming environment.

01-2009

Blauwe planeet

(Shapers)

This is an actually an older CD-Rom project I'd worked on before at Shapers for Thieme Meullenhoff. Within a week I created a Flash prototype that looked better and worked better than the original Director version.

11-2008

Rabobank unplugged

(Moodfactory)

Lead developer for a 1m by 2m touch screen interface navigating through lifesize videos.

10-2008

new Mitsubishi Colt

(Lukkien)

Lead developer for the new Colt site. A Flash site with lots of video interwoven with content. And a scrollable panoramic video with 3D sound.

06-2008

FC Walvisch

(FC Walvisch)

Re-design and creation of the site of one of the foremost Dutch sound studios.

01-2008

Nationale IQ test

(BNN)

Creation of the digital equivalent of a yearly TV questionaire.

11-2007

Elffantasy map

(Shapers)

An interactive zoomable map for the festival. All data on the map was loaded from a Google Earth kml file.

Generated by www.PDFonFly.com at 10/5/2010 6:13:46 AM

URL: http://ronvalstar.nl/cv.html

11-2007

Kosmonaut

(Kosmonaut)

Design and creation of a website that depicted a wooden desktop over which a camera pans, zooms and rotates.

07-2007

SFHorizon

(Shapers)

Concept and development of a 3D environment where predictions about the future where depicted as a starry wormhole.

07-2005

Ome Willem

(Ome Willem)

Interaction design, graphic design and development for the Ome Willem website.

01-2003

Kleuren Speuren

(Sikkens/Centraal Museum)

From concept to final product of a childrens CD-rom about colour.

side projects (short se

08-2010

Time

(Javascript, Google Docs)

To combine my curiosity about the abilities of Google Docs and the age of the universe and everything else I made a small application that shows you the relative distance in time between past occurences and future predictions. All the data is taken from a spreadsheet residing in the clouds at Google Docs

02-2009

Stampomatic

(PHP,XML,jQuery)

To extend my Servo-Croatian vocabulary I made a jQuery application with which you can translate words from one language to another. Then add the translations to categories which you can practice. Al the data including your progress in a certain category is stored locally by means of cookies.

02-2009

ffBatch

(PHP,XML,jQuery)

In my spare time I like making textures with Filter Forge. They also have a batch renderer but it has no interface, you can only work it command line. So I made an online interface to which you can upload a filter (XML), set all possible rendering and animation options, and subsequently download a zip file that contains all the files you need: a single click and your batch is rendering.

06-2008

SFBrowser

(jQuery, PHP)

Most content management systems have a fairly crummy way of uploading and managing files. With jQuery and PHP I made a very extensive file uploader that can be hooked onto any CMS. You can even port it to a different server side language through the use of connectors.

06-2008

Tinysort

(Javascript)

Tinysort is a tiny a jQuery plugin that only does one thing: it sorts the selectors return value in almost any possible way.

11-2007

PSP ebook reader

(PHP)

Generated by www.PDFonFly.com at 10/5/2010 6:13:46 AM URL: http://ronvalstar.nl/cv.html

Without modding my PSP I created an eBook reader for it. PHP runs through a folder containing eBook text files. It turns them into HTML which you can then put on your PSP to read.

10-2007

Perlin noise port from Java to Actionscript 3

(Flash Actionscript 3)

Since my Processing endavours I've grown quit fond of Perlin noise. The Flash implementation was rather poor so I converted Ken Perlins original Java class to Actionscript and implemented octaves, falloff and random seed.

02-2007

contributed 3D primitives to Papervision3D

(Flash Actionscript 3)

When I started with Papervision3D it had just been ported from as2 to as3. The only primitive it had then was a plane. So I contributed a number of primitives (cube, sphere, cylinder, cone) some of which still reside in there today.

06-2006

Strange attractor renderer

(Java, Processing)

This started of in Processing but soon grew into a Java project.

06-2005

The amazingly stupid frogs from space

(Flash Actionscript 2)

A Flash game in which you fly a ufo and abduct sheep by way of first contact.

languages

Dutch fluently English fluently

interests and/or hobbies

reading books ko ryu tai jutsu information visualisation typography nature microscopy (photography) growing plants collecting rocks/shells/insects programming Arduino math

Generated by www.PDFonFly.com at 10/5/2010 6:13:46 AM
URL: http://ronvalstar.nl/cv.html